Guide to the Workforce Developement Institute Unseenamerica NYS Photographs PHOTOS.280
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Workforce Developement Institute Unseenamerica NYS Photographs
2004-2010
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Workforce Development Institute
Murphy, Ed
PHOTOS.280
6 Linear Feet (10 drop-front boxes, two manuscript boxes)
Unseenamerica NYS is a photography and writing workshop class offered to working men and women across New York by the Workforce Development Institute.
Scope and Content Note
12 boxes of photographs, negatives, and printed material from unseen America: New York State, a project showcasing the lives and experiences of workers. Photographic prints include 10x15 black and white prints and 4x6 color and black and white photos. Box 12 contains a binder with photocopies of proofs from boxes 1-5. Photographs were taken beween 2004 and 2010 in many cities and towns in upstate New York, including Albany, Binghamton, Buffalo, Gloversville, Poughkeepsie, Purchase, and Utica. A project collaboration between the Workforce Development Institute, Bread & Roses, and SEIU/1199.
Separated Materials
Three sets of posters from Bread & Roses and Workforce Development Institute promoting specific labor unions were separated and added to the Tamiment/Wagner Poster collection.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Workforce Development Institute (WDI) is a New York State nonprofit that provides programs in workforce, economic, and community development in order to improve the lives of working families around the State. The WDI Art of Labor program provides photography, writing, and art workshops to capture stories of workers across New York. Unseenamerica NYS is a 10-12 week photography and writing workshop class offered to working men and women across New York.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Workforce Development Institute, under an agreement with Ed Murphy (executive director), 2011. The accession number associated with this gift is 2011.034.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Women's rights -- New York (State) -- New York.; Gay rights -- New York (State) -- New York.; Buffalo (N.Y.); Women -- Employment -- New York (State) -- New York; Albany (N.Y.); Workforce Development Institute; Murphy, Ed
- Unseen America - New York State, 2004-2010
  - Albany Spring, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albany Pride, 2005, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Binghamton, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Buffalo, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Gloversville, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hudson, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Kingston, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Massena, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Mineola, Long Island, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Niagara Falls, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Poughkeepsie, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Purchase, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Rochester, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Schenectady, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Syracuse, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Troy, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Troy: Our Story, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - USCRI Albany, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - USCRI Albany, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Utica Refugees, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Utica Veterans, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Chung, Daisy, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cook, Gail, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Cook, Gail – Bread & Roses, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - E.J., 2004 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Loose Photographs, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Murphy, Zoeann (?) - Gloversville, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Palmer, Mel, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Rouse, Sharon, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Stan, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Tammy, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Taylor, Ronald, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Unidentified, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Warren, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "1", 2004 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Around Gloversville, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Babies, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Buildings & Clowns, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cheri – Extra Negs, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Farm, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Farm Thing, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Images of Gloversville, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Kathy – Gloversville storefronts, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Kathy T. – Extra Negs, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Linda – Cats & Steam, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Linda – Extra Negs, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Pam – Extra Negs, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Pam – Chandelier, Glove Theater, Around Town, Gargoyle, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Petri Dishes, People, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Rural Kid on Tractor, Work Equipment, Little Actress, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Stan – Petri Dish, Grandma & baby, kids on couch, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Stan – Extra Negs, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Vickie Edick – Extra Negs, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - ?, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Amsterdam, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Gloversville, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Maher, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Poughkeepsie, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Purchase, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Purchase?, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Syracuse Class, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - USCRI, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Utica, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Colleen, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - George, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Janet, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Kate, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Linda, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Loose Photographs, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Ramesh, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Tammy, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Terry, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Tony, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Our Story Opening, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Syracuse "Extra" (George Smith's Photos), undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Published Catalogs, Pamphlets, and DVDs, 2004-2010 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Print promotional materials and announcements of exhibits and related events, 2004-2010 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - DVDs of Videos produced by WDI, 2004-2010 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - (2) DVD-Rs Containing a complete set of scans for photos in the project that were exhibited (they are labeled Images- WDI 1/2 and 2/2; WDI = Workforce Development Institute), 2004-2010 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - (2) DVD-Rs Containing Text documents (Class lists + contacts, captions, press releases, flyers) and Powerpoint presentation, 2004-2010 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Binder containing photocopies of proofs from boxes 1-5., 2004-2010 (Box 12)